<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Berlin Tour Guide</string>
    <!-- CATEGORY NAMES -->

    <string name="category_museums">MUSEUMS &amp; HISTORICAL PLACES</string>
    <string name="category_restaurants">RESTAURANTS</string>
    <string name="category_sights">SIGHTS &amp; ATTRACTIONS</string>
    <string name="category_activities">ACTIVITIES &amp; SHOPPING</string>

    <!-- PLACE NAMES -->

    <string name="museum_name_stasi_museum">Stasi Museum</string>
    <string name="museum_name_ddr_museum">DDR Museum</string>
    <string name="museum_name_museum_island">Museum Island</string>
    <string name="museum_name_sans_souci_palace">Sans Souci Palace</string>
    <string name="museum_name_holocaust_memorandum">Holocaust Memorandum</string>
    <string name="museum_name_topography_of_terrors">Topography Of Terrors</string>
    <string name="museum_name_berlin_wall">Berlin Wall</string>
    <string name="museum_name_reichstag">Reichstag</string>
    <string name="museum_name_marx_engels_forum">Marx - Engels Forum</string>
    <string name="museum_name_checkpoint_charlie">Checkpoint Charlie</string>

    <string name="restaurants_name_curry_36">Curry 36</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_mustafas_gemuse_kebap">Mustafa\'s Gemuse Kebap</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_burger_meister">Burger Meister</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_vapiano">Vapiano</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_zola">Zola</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hasir">Hasir</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_lindner">Lindner</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_block_house">Block House</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hokey_pokey">Hokey Pokey</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_oysterbar_kadewe">Oysterbar KaDeWe</string>

    <string name="sights_name_alexanderplatz">Alexanderplatz</string>
    <string name="sights_name_potsdamer_platz">Potsdamer Platz</string>
    <string name="sights_name_victoriapark">Victoria Park</string>
    <string name="sights_name_brandenburg_gate">Brandenburg Gate</string>
    <string name="sights_name_east_side_gallery">East Side Gallery</string>
    <string name="sights_name_hauptbahnhof">Hauptbahnhof</string>
    <string name="sights_name_gendarmenmarkt">Gendarmenmarkt</string>
    <string name="sights_name_botanischer_garten">Botanical Garden</string>
    <string name="sights_name_olympiastadion">Olympiastadion</string>
    <string name="sights_name_tiergarten">Tiergarten</string>

    <string name="activities_name_kadewe">KaDeWe</string>
    <string name="activities_name_ampelmann_shop">Ampelmann Shop</string>
    <string name="activities_name_classic_remise">Classic Remise</string>
    <string name="activities_name_markthalle_neun">Markthalle Neun</string>
    <string name="activities_name_berlin_philharmonic">Berlin Philharmonic</string>
    <string name="activities_name_tierpark">Tierpark</string>
    <string name="activities_name_mall_of_berlin">Mall Of Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_sony_center">Sony Center</string>
    <string name="activities_name_aquadom_and_sealife">Aquadom &amp; SeaLife</string>
    <string name="activities_name_trabi_tour">Trabi Tour</string>

    <!-- PLACE SHORT EXPLANATIONS -->

    <string name="museum_name_stasi_museum_short_explanation">Stasi Museum is a research and memorial centre concerning the political system of the former East Germany.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_ddr_museum_short_explanation">DDR Museum offers you a hands-on experience of everyday life in a state long gone, the life in the German Democratic Republic.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_museum_island_short_explanation">Museum Island is a unique ensemble of five museums on Spree Island in the district of Mitte. Entire complex is listed by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_sans_souci_palace_short_explanation">Stunning rococo Sanssouci Palace and its verdant gardens and terraced vineyards were the summer home of Friedrich the Great.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_holocaust_memorandum_short_explanation">Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe or Holocaust Memorial commemorates six million Jewish victims of Nazi Holocaust.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_topography_of_terrors_short_explanation">Topographie des Terrors is a center for the documentation of Nazi crimes, and now attracts hundreds of thousands of visitors every year.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_berlin_wall_short_explanation">Berlin Wall has long since disappeared from reunified Berlin. Memories of it, are still alive: remains and traces of the former border installations are being preserved for posterity.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_reichstag_short_explanation">Reichstag building with the famous glass dome is one of the most frequently visited sights in Berlin. It is seat of the German parliament, the Bundestag.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_marx_engels_forum_short_explanation">Marx-Engels-Forum near the Red Town Hall is a real GDR relic. It shows Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels as larger than life figures.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_checkpoint_charlie_short_explanation">Checkpoint Charlie was best-known border crossing between East and West Berlin during the Cold War. At the height of Berlin Crisis in 1961 U.S. and Soviet tanks faced each other here.</string>

    <string name="restaurants_name_curry_36_short_explanation">Curry 36 on Mehringdamm in Kreuzberg is the epitomy of Berlin Currywurst.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_mustafas_gemuse_kebap_short_explanation">Kebab at Mustafa\'s Veggie Kebab look vastly different than anywhere else for a good reason: they sell exclusively chicken kebab!</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_burger_meister_short_explanation">Directly under the subway rails at Schlesisches Tor in Kreuzberg you can find this small but delicious burger joint the Burgermeister.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_vapiano_short_explanation">The smell of freshly baked pizza, homemade fresh pasta, crisp salads, delicious antipasti and dolci this and much more is Vapiano.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_zola_short_explanation">The Paul-Lincke-Ufer in Kreuzberg serves Napolitan pizza at Zola.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hasir_short_explanation">Turkish restaurant is known across the city limits and attracts many tourists.
    Specialties include grilled lamb in different variations.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_lindner_short_explanation">Lindner always maintained the standards of their products. Their shop on Wittenbergplatz is a great place to enjoy their creations sitting in the sun.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_block_house_short_explanation">Block House is a Hamburg-based restaurant chain founded in 1968 that specializes in steaks.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hokey_pokey_short_explanation">Prenzlauer Berg\'s ice cream shop Hokey Pokey sells splendid ice cream made by a professional patissier.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_oysterbar_kadewe_short_explanation">Gourmet department of Kadewe is Europe\'s biggest food department in any shop with 34.000 products laid out on 7.000 square metres.</string>

    <string name="sights_name_alexanderplatz_short_explanation">Alexanderplatz is a central square and traffic junction in Berlin\'s Mitte district. One of city\'s the most visited squares and site of many attractions and sights in Berlin.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_potsdamer_platz_short_explanation">Potsdamer Platz has been redeveloped as the new centre of Berlin after the fall of the Wall. A bustling traffic intersection in the 1920s, it became desolate after WW II and part of the border strip.
    </string>
    <string name="sights_name_victoriapark_short_explanation">Viktoriapark is Berlin\'s highest inner city elevation with Kreuzberg. On the top of the mountain is the national monument of Schinkel, which is reminiscent of the victory against Napoleon.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_brandenburg_gate_short_explanation">Brandenburg Gate is Berlin\'s most famous landmark. A symbol of Berlin and German division during the Cold War, it is now a national symbol of peace and unity.
</string>
    <string name="sights_name_east_side_gallery_short_explanation">East Side Gallery, one of Berlin\'s most popular sights, is a former section of Berlin Wall. After fall of the Wall, artists have turned it into the largest open-air gallery in the world.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_hauptbahnhof_short_explanation">Berlin Hauptbahnhof is the most important passenger transport station in Berlin and at the same time the largest tower station in Europe.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_gendarmenmarkt_short_explanation">Gendarmenmarkt in the Mitte district is arguably Berlin\'s most beautiful square. It is the site of three impressive buildings: The German and the French Cathedral and Schinkel\'s Konzerthaus.
</string>
    <string name="sights_name_botanischer_garten_short_explanation">Botanical Garden in Berlin-Steglitz is one of the largest and most species-rich botanical gardens in the world.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_olympiastadion_short_explanation">Olympic Stadium is Berlin\'s largest sports stadium. Built for the 1936 Summer Olympic Games, it now hosts major sports and entertainment events.
</string>
    <string name="sights_name_tiergarten_short_explanation">Popular among locals and visitors alike, Tiergarten is Berlin\'s largest and most frequented inner-city park. It is ideal for a stroll, outdoor activities or a picnic.
</string>

    <string name="activities_name_kadewe_short_explanation">KaDeWe is Berlin\'s largest and most famous department store. Its 60,000 square meters of retail space and gourmet floor attract visitors from all over the world.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_ampelmann_shop_short_explanation">Inspired by the beloved East Berlin pedestrian traffic signal, Ampelmann is a well-known brand for a range of products that are perfect as Berlin souvenirs.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_classic_remise_short_explanation">Classic Remise is a place for motorcycle and automobile with specialization in the range of the classics, Oldtimer and collector vehicles.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_markthalle_neun_short_explanation">Markthalle Neun is a historic market hall, retailers primarily offer fair, organic and locally produced food.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_berlin_philharmonic_short_explanation">The Philharmonie is a showpiece of organic architecture. The very controversial building is today a model for concert halls all over the world.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_tierpark_short_explanation">One of Berlin\'s most prominent landmarks, Berlin Zoo is Germany\'s oldest zoo. It is considered to contain most comprehensive collection of species in the world.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_mall_of_berlin_short_explanation">Located between Potsdamer Platz and Friedrichstraße, Mall of Berlin shopping centre at Leipziger Platz offers various shopping facilities on four floors.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_sony_center_short_explanation">Sony Center on Potsdamer Platz stands out for its unique architecture. Ensemble of seven individual buildings houses cinemas, a museum, restaurants, offices and apartments.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_aquadom_and_sealife_short_explanation">AquaDom in Berlin is the largest, freestanding cylindrical aquarium in the world and has been in the CityQuartier DomAquarée in Mitte since May 2004.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_trabi_tour_short_explanation">Trabi Tour</string>

    <!-- PLACE EXPLANATIONS -->

    <string name="museum_name_stasi_museum_explanation">House 1 of the former headquarters of the Ministry for State Security (Stasi) now houses a research and memorial center focused on the GDR’s political system.

The original offices of Erich Mielke, the GDR’s last Minister for State Security, are the centerpiece of the exhibition, which is rounded off by sections devoted to the Stasi’s operational work, various aspects of the political system, and resistance and dissent in the GDR.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_ddr_museum_explanation">What has been preserved from the 40 years of the German Democratic Republic (GDR) or East Germany? Although many exhibitions have dealt with single GDR themes such as the Berlin Wall, State borders or the infamous Stasi, it wasn’t until the DDR Museum opened on July 15, 2006 that the multi-faceted particulars of everyday life in the GDR were finally gathered under one roof in the City Quartier Dom Aquarée. With its sworn mission of objectivity in its approach to facts and subjectivity in relating personal experience, the DDR Museum has welcomed over half a million visitors from all over the world, keen to dip into authentic everyday GDR living culture. How does it feel to live under surveillance? Whose nickname was Sudel Ede? How comfortable was a flat in the typical Plattenbau – the concrete slab prefabricated housing blocks common in the GDR - and how did it feel sit at the steering wheel of the tiny Trabant?
These questions and many others can be explored at Berlin’s DDR Museum in a lively and interactive fashion. The museum doesn’t simply cater for “Ostalgie” fans. It sees itself as a column in the social analysis and cultural preservation of the former DDR. It offers a more popular perspective with a local history approach in addition to the more standard Wall or Stasi exhibitions. The Head of Research Dr. Stefan Wolle took on the task of ensuring that the museum would stand out as an important repository of German cultural history, to be passed on to future generations.

Visitors are invited to broaden their knowledge, to see through stereotypes and clichés, to rethink and to experience history at first hand. The museum’s exhibits are interactive. The idea is to take part with all one’s senses gathering experiences as you go along. The permanent exhibition draws attention to 16 main areas of life in the GDR. Housing, Work, Leisure, Fashion and Culture are amongst the themes to explore. Over 300 former GDR citizens contributed to the collection with exhibits and by donating personal effects and belongings resulting in an authentic mix of memorabilia. An Erika Typewriter, the Karat Schrankwand, the Stern radio, photographs, clothing are vital elements which bring the visitor face to face with day-to-day reality behind the Iron Curtain. The five most popular highlights are the Trabant, the authentic Plattenbau living room, a school satchel with school material including school reports and children’s exercise books, a cupboard full of authentic GDR clothing and the area dedicated to the Stasi. </string>
    <string name="museum_name_museum_island_explanation">Berlin\'s Museumsinsel (Museum Island) is a unique ensemble of five museums, including the Pergamon Museum - built on a small island in Berlin\'s Spree River between 1824 and 1930. A cultural and architectural monument of great significance, it was awarded UNESCO World Heritage Status in 1999. Berlin\'s own Acropolis of the arts is considered unique because it illustrates the evolution of modern museum design over the course of the 20th century and its collections span six thousand years of human artistic endeavour. Museum Island was designed as a modern Forum Romanum
Its artefacts, originating largely from the private collections of the Prussian royal family, have been administered since 1918 by the Stiftung Preußischer Kulturbesitz (Prussian Cultural Heritage Foundation). The first museum, the Altes Museum (1830) considered to be Karl Friedrich Schinkel\'s neoclassical masterpiece is Germany\'s oldest museum. The development of the area as a museum complex and the construction of the other four museums stemmed from King Friedrich Wilhelm\'s (1840-1861) romantic vision of a refuge of the arts and sciences similar to the Forum of ancient Rome. UNESCO defined it \'an outstanding example of the Enlightenment vision of making art publicly accessible, given material form in a central urban setting\".
Full-scale renovation of the Museum Island underway since 1999
The Master Plan for the full-scale renovation and modernisation of the area, adopted and underway since 1999, aims to turn the site into a state-of-the-art cultural location. Amongst the planned additions are the architectural promenade linking the buildings, infrastructural developments including a new, central entrance building by British architect David Chipperfiled, with exhibition areas, cafés, and museum shops - the restoration of the Old National Gallery\'s gardens to their former 1900 appearance and the fourth wing of the Pergamon Museum. Museum Island is located on Spree Island where Berlin originated
Berlin\'s owns Treasure Island is directly accessible on the left side of the German Historical Museum – opposite Berlin\'s Staatsoper on Unter den Linden boulevard – only a short walk across the ornate, sculptured Schlossbrücke (Palace Bridge). The site is of topographical and historical interest as it is here, in the small Spreeinsel (Spree Island) that the city of Berlin originated as the twin 13th century settlements Berlin and Cölln. Old and New Museum on Museum Island
Following Schinkel\'s 1830s Altes Museum, Friedrich Wilhelm IV commissioned the Neues Museum in 1859 to house the Egyptian and prehistoric collections. Over 200 million Euros have been earmarked to renovate the museum, which displays the Egyptian Papyrus collection and the Library of Antiquity and Nefertiti in much reduced circumstances in a reflecting glass box. Old National Gallery and Bode Museum on Museum Island
The Alte Nationalgalerie followed in 1876, built by Johann Heinrich Strack, Friedrich August Stüler\'s successor, as an elevated temple of antiquity for 19th century German and European painting collections. It reopened in 2001, with works from Monet, Manet, Renoir and Caspar David Friedrich. The Baroque Bode Museum (1904), originally Kaiser Friedrich\'s Museum for European Renaissance art was named after its first director, Wilhelm von Bode in 1956. Renowned for its sculpture collection and Museum of Byzantine Art, it finally reopened in 2006 after a five and a half years\' renovation. Pergamon Museum on Museum Island
The most well-known of the complex, Alfred Mussel\'s Pergamon Museum (1930) was built following the need for additional exhibit space to house the artefacts from the 19th century excavations of German archeologists in Pergamon and Asia Minor at a time when Heinrich Schliemann found Priam\'s treasure. The Pergamon museum continues to attract one million visitors a year from all over the world to marvel at the Market Gate of Miletus and the Ishtar Gate. Due to extensive renovations, the Pergamon Altar hall is currently closed to visitors. It is scheduled to reopen in late 2019.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_sans_souci_palace_explanation">For normal folk, Potsdam’s Sanssouci is a relaxing royal treat only 30 minutes away by train from bustling Berlin. In French, the palace’s name means “without a care;” it was a quiet refuge for the Prussian king. His final wish was to be buried there, a desire not granted until after German reunification.
This UNESCO World Heritage Site, built between 1745 and 1747, is known for its treasures inside and out.

Highlights include the white and gold Marble Hall reception area, loosely based on the Pantheon in Rome, the many paintings by one of Friedrich’s favorite artists, Antoine Watteau, and the Voltaire Room, with its carvings of birds, flowers and fruits, named after the French philosopher and frequent palace guest. The large landscaped park is dotted with fountains, with faux ruins and classical statues among the many points of interest. Also at Sanssouci is the splendid Neues Palace (New Palace), added to commemorate the end of the Seven Year’s War, a reconstructed Dutch windmill, the Orangerie, which houses a gallery, and the Drachenhaus (Dragon House), a pagoda-style building that now holds a pleasant café for park visitors.

Sanssouci is located in Potsdam, just outside of Berlin, and is easily accessible by public transportation and car. The site, which stretches out for 2 kilometers west of Potsdam’s city center, is open later from Spring to Fall; music festivals are held annually on the grounds. The palace and individual buildings require ticket purchase for entry; many are only accessible with an official guided tour. Day tickets and family tickets providing access to multiple museums are available. If you are visiting with children don’t miss the Historische Mühle (Historical Windmill).</string>
    <string name="museum_name_holocaust_memorandum_explanation">Berlin\'s Holocaust Memorial, located in Mitte on a stretch of the former \"death strip\" where the Wall once stood near Brandenburg Gate, is Berlin\'s stunning monument to the Holocaust, dedicated to the Jewish victims of the Nazi genocide of World War II. Impressive in its awesome grey soberness, rather than sombreness, it includes an underground Ort der Information (Information Centre) located on the south-eastern side of the memorial grounds, accessible via two flights of stairs or a lift.
Information Centre at the Memorial
The 800 square meters Information Centre complements the abstraction of the memorial with personal documentation about individuals and families. This includes biographical details, recordings and information about memorial sites throughout Germany and Europe. Documenting the universal issue of genocide, the centre represents a central focus on the diverse memorial sites across Germany which stress the living memory aspect of remembrance. In Berlin an example of this is the Stolpersteine (tripping stones) initiative – plaques on street pavements, usually outside the house\'s main entrance, commemorating deported Jewish residents.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_topography_of_terrors_explanation">The site known since 1987 as the \"Topography of Terror\" was the central location from which the Nazis palnned and managed most of their crimes. Here, between 1933 and 1945, the most important institutions of the Nazi terror apparatus of the SS and police operated from the Secret State Police Office, the Reich SS Leadership, and the Reich Security Main Office. Partially destroyed during the war, rendered unrecognizable after the war by demolition and conversion, and eventually forgotten, this historic site was rediscovered in the early 1980s and gradually reestablished in the historical memory of Berlin and the Federal Republic of Germany. What had been a partial wasteland in the shadow of the Berlin Wall was ultimately transormed into a center for the documentation of Nazi crimes, and now attracts hundreds of thousands of visitors every year.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_berlin_wall_explanation">In the years following the events of 13 August 1961, the GDR leadership expanded the border fortifications between East and West Berlin to create a system of many different control elements. The border walls and fences were as high as 3.60 meters in places, while the “no man’s land” that separated them was between five and several hundred meters wide. Today most of that area has been built over. In some parts, green spaces or memorial sites contribute to making this a “commemorative landscape.”</string>
    <string name="museum_name_reichstag_explanation">The Reichstag building was completed in 1894 following German national unity and the establishment of the German Reich in 1871. After a complete restoration of Paul Wallot\'s original building, the Bundestag reconvened here in Sir Norman Foster\'s spectacularly restored Reichstag building on April 19, 1999. Following German reunification on October 3, 1990 the Bundestag (German Federal Parliament) decided, one year later, to make the Reichstag the seat of Parliament in Berlin, the restored capital of reunited Germany.
History of the Reichstag building
The Reichstag building was completed in 1894 following German national unity and the establishment of the German Reich in 1871. Under the attentive eye of Kaiser Wilhelm II, Paul Wallot\'s Reichstag competition winner of 1882 was a synthesis of High Renaissance and classical motifs such as the façade of columned porticos. It already included a modern glass and steel dome. The building\'s grandeur was accentuated by an imposing projecting columned entrance supporting a triangular gable and a wide flight of steps that must be climbed to reach the main entrance portal. The result was a four-wing structure with two inner courtyards and a central plenary chamber and an emperor\'s crown at a height of 75m on the lantern. Ironically, the building\'s site was considered slightly unfortunate at the time because its entrance was facing the wrong side – West - with its back to the imperial Schloss and the 19th century city centre. The famous inscription - \"DEM DEUTSCHEN VOLK\" - (to the German nation), a 1916 addition by Peter Behrens, still towers above the monumental entrance.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_marx_engels_forum_explanation">On the Spandauer Straße is a \"green area\", which is actually a red - the Marx-Engels-Forum, a relic from the GDR era. There, the larger-than-life figures represent the founding fathers of scientific communism, Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels.

The residential and commercial buildings that once stood on this square were destroyed during the Second World War and demolished after 1945. The current monument was inaugurated on 4 April 1986, since then Marx and Engels return to the Palace of the Republic. The area was created according to plans by Ludwig Engelhardt. In the center is his bronze Marx-Engels monument. Behind it stands a relief wall by Werner Stötzer made of Bulgarian marble. It shows groups of people in the early capitalist world. In contrast, the bronze reliefs by Margret Midell: scenes of life in a liberated society. Between relief and philosopher duo are steel steles with photo documents of the labor movement.</string>
    <string name="museum_name_checkpoint_charlie_explanation">Checkpoint Charlie, along with Glienicker Brücke (Glienicke Bridge) was the best known border crossing during the Cold War. The sign, which became a symbol of the division of Cold War Berlin and read like a dire warning to those about to venture beyond the Wall – \"YOU ARE LEAVING THE AMERICAN SECTOR\" – in English, Russian, French and German - stood here. It is today an iconic marker of territorial boundary and political division. Until the fall of the Berlin Wall on November 9, 1989, it signified the border between West and East, Capitalism and Communism, freedom and confinement.
Checkpoint Charlie is a must-see sight in Berlin
The spot remains a must-see sight in Berlin with huge historical and emotional resonance, even accounting for the fact that there is remarkably little left to recall the atmosphere of pre-1989 days. An enormous amount of debating went into deciding what should be left here and preserved for Berliners and visitors to see in the future.
 Confrontation at Checkpoint Charlie in 1961
Historically, the site is important because from 1961 to 1990 it functioned as the main entry and departing point for diplomats, journalists and non-German visitors who were allowed to enter East Berlin on a one day visa after exchanging their Deutsch Marks on a one-to-one basis for East German currency. More dramatically, US and Soviet tanks had a close encounter here in October 1961 when J.F. Kennedy and Nikita Khrushchev\'s tanks faced each other in an acrimonious moment feared around the World as a possible lead up to World War III.
Checkpoint Charlie after the fall of the Wall
The wooden barrack where visitors to the Russian Sector (East Berlin) were once obliged to pass through for vetting was removed. Reconstruction has included a US Army guardhouse and a copy of the original border sign. The original white booth which served as the official gateway between East and West can be seen in the Allierten Museum in Berlin-Dahlem. Cobblestones mark the exact spot of the former border and the poignant photograph by Frank Thiel of an American and Soviet soldier can be seen here. Memorabilia includes the nearby Café Adler, a hotspot for journalists and spies in the past where informers met their counterparts.

The Museum, known as Haus am Checkpoint Charlie, contains the best documentation available on the many escape attempts from East to West. The original Checkpoint sign is exhibited here.
Booming city district at Checkpoint Charlie
Ironically, the New Berlin has turned this area into an entry, rather than departure point, to a new kind of American sector. Today\'s Friedrichstraße, with its Manhattan style office district, its new buildings by international architects such as Philip Johnson, who created the American Business Center, is the fruit of the millions in corporate investment which rebuilt this central part of Berlin in the 1990s.</string>

    <string name="restaurants_name_curry_36_explanation">Curry 36 on Mehringdamm in Kreuzberg is the epitomy of Berlin Currywurst. The legendary snack stall has been serving its customers for more than 30 years, always with the classic - currywurst with or without casing! Several stars and celebrities have eaten here and hosts of locals, night owls, tourists and curry aficionados, and that day and night. And of course you can get more than just currywurst here, fries red/white, bockwurst, a genuine Berlin Bulette and much more - of course with curry at Curry 36.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_mustafas_gemuse_kebap_explanation">The result has an unforgettable taste, in addition to the chickenmeat they use fresh feta and grilled vegetables. You don\'t find this anywhere else.

On top of that, the kebab has a secret ingredient which is not revealed. Kebab purists may argue that this is not genuine, but the customers there like it even better.

At lunch time there is a long waiting line on the shop at Mehringdamm but despite the crowd pressure, Mohammad and Hassan serve the people always with a smile.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_burger_meister_explanation">They make daily fresh burger variations such as the \"Hausmeista\", the \"Bar-B-Q-Burger\" or the hearty \"Meister of all Trades\" with double meat and double cheese. The juicy meat patties are 100% pure beef and grilled right in front of the waiting customers.

Burgermeister offers as sidedish normal fries, cheese fries or chili-cheese fries scalloped with cheese, beef, onions and fresh jalapeños. Since their space is limited at Burgermeister, you have to be prepared to wait a little, depending on how busy the place is.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_vapiano_explanation">At Vapiano, guests enjoy their favorite dishes, which are cooked to order and always fresh. The Vapianos invite you to a Mediterranean break in a cosmopolitan and communicative atmosphere - including a cozy glass of wine in the evening.

The secret of Vapiano\'s success is freshness - freshness in the ingredients, preparation and thinking. Every single Vapiano in the world produces eleven types of pasta (two of wholegrain spelled), pizza dough and sauces every day, sometimes even in the middle of the dining room, in the glass Manifattura. Even the dressings, cakes and dolci (desserts) are freshly made or baked daily - and all over the world in all vapianos.

In the show kitchen every pasta dish, every pizza and every salad is individually prepared in front of and for the guest \"à la minute\". This interactive front cooking concept allows the guest to directly communicate their preferences and wishes to the chef during preparation. So personal favorite dishes are cooked, which can be easily adapted to alternative diets.

As a result, guests with vegan or vegetarian dietary awareness as well as food intolerance will find what Vapiano needs to suit their personal needs without having to compromise.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_zola_explanation">Napolitan pizza, in which the pizza is authentically reduced occupied and baked in the cupola to southern Italy model at 450 degrees within seconds to crispy perfection, is currently very popular in Berlin. This is exactly how pizza specialties are served in the cozy Zola restaurant on Paul-Lincke-Ufer in Kreuzberg. The tavern-like pizzeria Zola can be reached via a backyard and reduced and sober but very comfortable, furnished. The lively restaurant makes you feel right at home as a visitor. The central element of the Zola is the impressive, wood-fired pizza oven from Naples, in which the pizzas are finished in 90 seconds.

The interior is bright and friendly. The stone walls are white and natural, the windowsills are made of wood panels, there are white wooden tables and wooden chairs. Candles are stuck in wax-covered bottlenecks and provide a cozy atmosphere. Serves pizza creations with the freshest ingredients such as buffalo mozzarella, fruity tomatoes, walnuts, capers, anchovies or olives. There is a small wine selection. The selection on the menu is manageable, but nothing misses and the prices are absolutely fair for the location.

The Zola spreads a comforting industrial charm and attracts tourists in addition to many regular visitors from the neighborhood. Although the Zola has Polish owners, the pizza is still typically Italian and one of the best in the city.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hasir_explanation">The Hasır in Adalbertstraße is the nucleus of all Hasır restaurants. Opened in 1984, today it is a Kreuzberg institution in which a great deal of Turkish regulars mix with Berliners and international guests. Kreuzberg nights are not only long - but do not end there. 24 hours is the Hasır, Adalbertstr. 10 is open and there is no time to eat kebab or spoon the quick lentil soup.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_lindner_explanation">When it comes to baked goods, Lindner will not move away from quality and tradition. This delikatessen store has been baking the dough for its LINDNER Krustenbrot (\"Crust Bread\") for 50 years in a very special way to preserve aroma and freshness of the bread.

For connoisseurs: Lindner\'s Krustenbrot is made with a flour mixture of 80% rye flour and 20% wheat flour with natural type III sourdough, that has been fermenting for 24 hours. The bread gets baked twice in a brick oven to get the closed, strong crust covering the entire outside of the bread conserving its aromas.

Next to other rye brown breads (rye and wheat and also rye and spelt), Butter Lindner has high-class organic breads, wholegrain breads and wheat breads in their assortment. In addition to many special breads and bread rolls, Butter Lindner\'s strong suit are cake and pastry creations, like for example their Bauerntorte (Farmers\' Tarte) - a cake mainstay for decades. In any way, don\'t fail to sample their macarons - something small and sweet to get you through the day with a smile.</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_block_house_explanation">The usual good quality of the steaks - \"crispy on the outside, soft pink and juicy on the inside\" - has been making the family business successful for decades and throughout Germany. How about an alternative to lunch with Viennese beef goulash in savory onion sauce?</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hokey_pokey_explanation">Hokey Pokey is much more than your corner shop with ice cream, this place is an ice cream patisserie, one of the best-known in all of Berlin. A while ago, Hokey Pokey hit the headlines all over town, when the waiting lines for the shop were beyond belief. Their ice-cream is absolute high-end and delicious, with outstanding ingredients like finest chocolate, whole nuts and fresh fruit.

These quality standards are rather unusual for an ice cream shop, but they come with a history: Owner and ice cream patissier Niko Robert is a master of his trade, he worked before as patissier in the luxury hotel Ritz Carlton. His own ice cream shop was a dream come true for him.

The shop itself is bright with a very friendly atmosphere. The various ice creams are presented behind an arched glass sales table and their delicious aspect really makes it hard to choose. Don\'t miss out on trying the name-giving flavour of the store, HokeyPokey, supposedly New Zeanland\'s most favourite ice cream. It\'s a traditionally crafted vanilla ice cream with real Bourbon Vanilla and crunchy caramel crispies. A real go-getter!

</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_oysterbar_kadewe_explanation">The Oyster bar of the gourmet floor of KaDeWe is legendary. Many illustrious guests from actress Hildegard Knef to politician Joschka Fischer have enjoyed this delicacy here already. So, if your parents on their Berlin visit have oysters and champagne at the KaDeWe, they will mingle with the well-off West-Berlin crowd and feel totally self-indulgent.

The KaDeWe is also modern, to the great happiness of kids and the age group of the 20 somethings. One of the most recent favourites is the \"New Burger\", serving gourmet burgers made of Black Angus, lobster tail or vegetarian.

From the pâtisserie with its mouth-watering creations, over tea, chocolate, wine and cheese - there is literally nothing you will not find on the gourmet floor. And all over the floor, the presentation of the articles is just a sight to behold - only at KaDeWe food shopping is also a feast for the eyes.</string>

    <string name="sights_name_alexanderplatz_explanation">\"Alex\" to Berliners, a cattle market in the Middle Ages, a military parade square and an exercise ground for nearby barracks until the mid 19th century - Alexanderplatz is the square named to honour Alexander I, Tsar of Russia, on his visit to Berlin in 1805. It was here that Alfred Döblin took the pulse of the cosmopolitan metropolis portrayed in his 1929 novel \"Berlin Alexanderplatz\" filmed by Fassbinder for a TV series as a portrait of the bustling city in the 1920s before the imminent Nazi takeover. Fast forward to more recent times, one million people congregated here, on 4 November 1989 to demonstrate against the GDR regime shortly before the fall of the Berlin Wall. This was the largest anti-government demonstration in its history.
 Alexanderplatz epitomizes Berlin\'s urban history
Layer upon layer of Berlin\'s urban history is located in Alexanderplatz, interweaving centuries of social, political, and architectural history and repeatedly the subject of public debate and urban design competitions. The transformation of Alexanderplatz into a modern transit junction and shopping area came about during the second half of the 19th century with developments such as the construction of the S-Bahn, Berlin\'s surface rail network in 1882 and the underground railway from 1913. Devasted during the war the square gradually developed into the pedestrian zone during the 1960s becoming a popular if rather amorphous urban area.
 Alexanderplatz: Centre of East Berlin
Many of the well known buildings, examples of East Berlin\'s attempt to compete with the Western side\'s own in-your-face high-rises were erected during this time: The \"Hotel Stadt Berlin\" – a 123 meters high hotel, the \"Haus des Lehrers\" (Teachers\' House), a venue for pedagogues which remained more of a representative façade than a real educational forum, the \"Haus des Reisens\" (House of Travel) with a slightly amusing ring to it given the notorious travel restrictions during the GDR, and the publishing house building - today\'s Berliner Verlag – with offices of the Berlin daily, Berliner Zeitung.
 Socialist urban aesthetics at Alexanderplatz
In the 1970s under Erich Honecker Alexanderplatz became an experiment in socialist urban aesthetics. The honeycomb aluminium facade of the former \"Centrum Warenhaus\", (Kaufhof Group today) was the largest department store in the GDR and is today a transformed department store designed by Josef Paul Kleihues. Major sights at Alexanderplatz
Amongst the sights to look out for here are the 365 metre TV Tower, Berlin\'s highest construction topped by a globe (turned into a pink football during the 2006 World Cup Event) with a rotating viewing platform. The \"Brunnen der Völkerfreundschaft\" (Fountain of Friendship amongst Peoples) and the landmark World Time Clock erected in 1969 serve as popular meeting places. Berolina House by Peter Behrens now houses a large retail clothing store. The Alexa shopping mall was opened in 2007, and a multiplex cinema attracts a number of film enthusiasts every day.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_potsdamer_platz_explanation">Berlin\'s Potsdamer Platz is the most striking example of the urban renewal that turned Berlin into the \"New Berlin\" in the 1990s although it is not, strictly-speaking, a square. The area today consists of the three developments known as Daimler City (1998), the Sony Centre (2000) and the Beisheim Centre (2004), which literally transformed the dormant wasteland where the Berlin Wall stood between east and west Berlin until 1989.
The debate around redeveloping Potsdamer Platz
The challenge of rebuilding the heart of post Cold War Berlin was no trifling matter – how to transform a desolate sandy wasteland into the new German capital\'s city centre. At stake was nothing less than making a statement on the fundamental principles of urban design at the end of the 20th century. Many issues needed to be addressed. How to reconcile public against commercial interests, the integration of two transport systems, road and infrastructural planning affecting the new re-united centre, limiting traffic in the inner city area and incorporating ecological considerations, deciding on the style of architecture - Manhattan high-rise buildings or lower housing, traditional, futuristic or avant-garde?
Potsdamer Platz today: A mixture of American and European city design
The long debates about the future of Potdamer Platz needed to resolve the issue of bringing authentic metropolitan life into an area which had been dead for years – integrating residential accommodation with shopping, leisure and business needs to ensure that the area live around-the-clock.

What can be seen today is believed to have resulted in a successful compromise - a mixture of the American plaza feel at the Sony Centre and a tree-lined European downtown around the Marlene Dietrich Platz producing a lively, buzzing atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_victoriapark_explanation">For only 100 years, only the Viktoriapark quenched the longing for green in the Kreuzberg Häusermeer. Fortunately, this is not the case today. But despite numerous alternatives, the park is still popular and well attended. At peak hours, tables and chairs for the family picnic are ever in the pond, and in the central beer garden are the famous Kieznächte as long as ever. In rainy weather, however, romantics get their money\'s worth.

History of the Victoria Park
The year 1888, when Berlin decided to create a park on Kreuzberg, was a fateful year. In March had with Emperor Frederick III. (1831-1888), a liberal-minded Hohenzoller ascended the throne, advocating a strengthening of parliament. His English wife Viktoria (1840-1901), daughter of the legendary Queen Victoria, was a critic of the military tradition and the hegemonic ambitions of Prussia. After only 99 days reign, however, the hope for liberalization of the still young German Reich was gone: The prudent monarch died, and under his son and successor Wilhelm II (1859-1941) began the arms race, which eventually led Europe into catastrophe.

Viktoriapark in memory of the English royal family
In memory of the empress from the English royal family, which Germany had been granted only for a short time, the green project on Kreuzberg received the name Viktoriapark. A British note is here but in vain. With its wild waterfall in a rocky mountain backdrop, this park has a deeply romantic character and thus reflects the typically German tendency to transfigure nature - a trait that unfolded in the 19th century, especially in the visual arts.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_brandenburg_gate_explanation">Brandenburg Gate is one of Berlin\'s most important monuments – a landmark and symbol all in one with over two hundred years of history. A former symbol of the divided city, it drew visitors who used to climb an observation platform in order to get a glimpse of the world behind the Iron Curtain, on the other side of the barren \"death-strip\" which separated East from West Berlin, geographically and politically. It was here that on June 12, 1987, Ronald Regan issued his stern command to his cold war adversary admonishing him with the words: \"Mr. Gorbachov – tear down this wall!\". The speech delivered to West Berliners was also audible on the east side of the Gate and echoed President von Weizsacker’s words which translate as: \"The German question is open as long as the Brandenburg Gate is closed.\"
Brandenburg Gate has turned into a symbol of unity
When Germany was reunified following the fall of the Berlin in November 1989 Brandenburg Gate quickly reinvented itself into the New Berlin\'s symbol of unity. It was officially opened to traffic on December 22, 1989 and 100,000 people came to celebrate the occasion. Unfortunately this also resulted in severe damage to the monument which needed to be restored and was only officially reopened on October 3, 2002.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_east_side_gallery_explanation">The East Side Gallery is a 1.3 kilometre long painted stretch of the former Berlin Wall along Mühlenstraße in former East Berlin. It is the largest open-air gallery in the world with over one hundred original mural paintings. Galvanised by the extraordinary events which were changing the world, artists from all around the globe rushed to Berlin after the fall of the Wall, leaving a visual testimony of the joy and spirit of liberation which erupted at the time.
East Side Gallery is a monument to freedom of expression
Wall murals had previously been a highlight for visitors and a Berlin attraction for years but were only to be found on the western side of the Wall. The artists transformed the grey concrete rearticulating this into a lasting expression of freedom and reconciliation.
 East Side Gallery Paintings
Some of the best known paintings such as \"The Mortal Kiss\" by Dmitri Vrubel, of Erich Honecker and Leonid Brezhnev\'s mouth-to-mouth embrace and Birgit Kinder\'s Trabi (Trabant) crashing through the Wall. They have provided popular postcard material until today. The paintings which still reflect the patchwork, eclectic and bohemian atmosphere of Berlin today are a mixed bag of surreal images, political statements and graffiti-like effusions stretching from the Oberbaum Bridge to Ostbahnhof train station.
Restoration of the East Side Gallery
The East Side Gallery is a listed monument. Damaged by vandalism, pollution and weather conditions, the paintings were restored in 2009 by the same artists who originally created the works after the Fall of the Wall.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_hauptbahnhof_explanation">With around 300,000 passengers a day, it is ranked fourth in Hamburg, Munich and Frankfurt (Main) by the most frequented long-distance train stations of Deutsche Bahn and is one of the 21 stations of the highest station category 1 of DB Station and Service.

The intersection station with 14 platform tracks is the connecting point between passenger (Intercity Express, Intercity / Euro City, HBX, EuroNight, Locomore) and suburban traffic (S-Bahn, Regionalbahn, Regional-Express).

The connection to the Berlin Underground via the subway station of the same name, which is still the end point of the 1.8 kilometer long line U55 to the station Brandenburger Tor, remains until the closing of the gap to Alexanderplatz station by the western extension of the line U5 a torso. If this goes into operation according to the current planning 2020, the U55 will merge in the U5. Other public transport connections exist in front of the station with the inner-city bus traffic (including metro and night buses) and the tram (lines M5, M8 and M10) of the BVG.

The striking building was designed by the architect Meinhard von Gerkan. Together with the station, a new north-south railway line was put into operation on 28 May 2006 through the tunnel north-south long-distance railway, which realizes through the so-called \"mushroom concept\" a complete conversion and reorganization of rail passenger transport in Berlin.

On the area north of the Spreebogens were already Lehrter station from 1868 to 1951 and from 1882 to 2002 the Lehrter city station.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_gendarmenmarkt_explanation">The Gendarmenmarkt is arguably Berlin\'s most magnificent square. It is best known for the architectural trio composed of the German and French cathedrals \(Deutscher und Franzosischer Dom\) and Schinkel\'s Konzerthaus \(concert hall\) which together form one of the most stunning ensembles in Berlin. The \"domes\" refer to the domed tower structures erected in 1785 by architect Carl von Gontard. They were mainly intended to add stature and grandeur to the two buildings.
Gendarmenmarkt\: Name derives from Prussian regiment of Huguenots soldiers
The square dates back to 1700, part of King Friedrick I\'s plan for Friedrichstadt, an emerging new quarter of Berlin, where the recently expelled French Protestants or Huguenots had settled following the Edict of Potsdam in 1685 which granted them asylum in the Prussian capital. The name is in fact of French origin as \"Gens d\'arms\", which was a Prussian regiment consisting of Huguenots soldiers.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_botanischer_garten_explanation">The botanical garden in the Steglitz district, designed by the architect Alfred Koerner and directed by the garden director Adolf Engler in 1897-1910, is one of the largest and most species-rich botanical gardens in the world, with 43 hectares and about 20,000 plant species. In an exemplary way, he represents the garden art of the late 19th century oriented towards Peter Lenné and Gustav Meyer.

Construction of the Botanical Garden
The facility, now a central facility of the Free University, consists of three areas: the park-like arboretum (wood and rose collection), the exposure of worldwide plant geographic formations, and the systematic department with about 1500 species of plants. In the years 1981-83, a 3000 square meter large fragrance and tactile garden for the visually impaired and wheelchair users was also created. Depending on the season different signposted paths lead through the garden past the most beautiful plants and flowers.

Showhouses in the botanical garden
Fifteen greenhouses are geometrically located on the eastern edge of the park, including the 1907-high, 25-meter-high and 1700-square-meter, large tropical greenhouse, one of the largest in the world, and an example of nineteenth-century glass-steel architecture , In front of it is the Victoria House, in the immediate vicinity are further, 1980-87 under the direction of the architect Engelbert Kremser renewed greenhouses.

Botanical Museum
In the years 1905/06, the botanical museum at the entrance Königin-Luise-Straße was created from the holdings of the former royal herbarium on the grounds of the former Botanical Garden in Schöneberg (now Heinrich-v. Kleist Park). In addition to extensive scientific plant collections - including the general herbarium with around 3.5 million Herbarbögen - it also includes the Schaumuseum, the only purely botanical museum in Europe. In addition to numerous models of the plant kingdom, among other things, the vegetable gifts of Egyptian pharaohs graves can be studied here.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_olympiastadion_explanation">Berlin\'s Olympiastadion and Glockenturm (Olympic Stadium and Bell Tower) was built for the 1936 Olympic Games when the 2400m horse-racing track in the Grunewald district, by Otto March 1909, was demolished in 1934 to make room for a new National Stadium designed by March\'s sons Werner and Walter March and supervised by Hitler\'s Imperial Interior Ministry. The Nazi-era monumentalist stadium and the exhibition in the Bell Tower carry vivid memories of the iconic images of African-American sprinter Jesse Owens whose historic four-medal Olympic victory shook Hitler\'s theory of the superiority of the Aryan race.
Olympic Stadium was built as part of a full-scale sports complex
Werner March\'s project for the 1936 Olympic Games – redesigned in typical Fascist monumental grandeur was intended as a full-scale sports complex - an Olympic Square, an Olympic Stadium seating 110,000 spectators and a track field known as Maifeld intended as a marching ground for mass rallies of up to 500,000 people and an Olympic swimming pool. The Waldbühne, one of Berlin\'s most popular open-air venues today, with 25,000 seats was built for gymnastics competitions. A 78m Olympic tower – The Bell Tower - completed the ensemble. Architecturally the Reich Sports Field attempted to draw effect from the interplay of architectural forms, nature and sculpture as a backdrop to national and organised events such as those depicted in Leni Riefenstahl\'s controversial films which orchestrated and immortalised the cultural aesthetic of National Socialism. Renovation and modernization of the Olympic Stadium
The site was reopened in 1946 when the British troops stationed in Berlin hosted and 8- nation track-and-field competition for Allied Forces soldiers. After the fall of the Wall in 1989 Berlin\'s bid for the 2004 Olympics failed and in 1998 the Berlin Senate took the final decision for the full transformation of the former complex into a modern multifunctional sports venue redeveloped by architects Gerkan Marg and Partner Group.
A multi-functional sports and events arena
The final, comprehensive renovation and modernization of the new Stadium took four years and was completed in 2004 complying with the highest requirements of the monument conservation orders and global sports events as a multi-functional sports and events arena which can seat up to 76,000 spectators. On July 9, 2006 Berlin\'s Olympia Stadium hosted the FIFA Soccer World Cup final between France and Italy.
Visiting the Olympic Stadium
The Bell Tower with the Visitor\'s Centre and the German Historical Museum Exhibition on the ground floor -\"Historic Site: The Olympic Grounds 1909 – 1936 – 2006\" was fittingly remodernised for the 2006 World Cup event. Highlights include the new glass lift and an observation deck.
To explore the Olympic Stadium grounds guided tours are available daily as well as audio-guides. Tours include the usually off-limits areas such as the VIP lounges, the high tech floodlights and giant screens, 25 info points documenting the history of the complex and even the locker and changing room areas of Berlin\'s Bundesliga Football Club, Hertha BSC.</string>
    <string name="sights_name_tiergarten_explanation">Tiergarten in Berlin refers to the parliamentary, government and diplomatic district as well as to Berlin\'s largest and most popular inner-city park. The Tiergarten (animal park) and former hunting ground is Berlin\'s best known park because of its centrality. It’s a favourite with locals and visitors, wonderful for a stroll, a breath of fresh air, a picnic, cycling or a jog or just kicking a ball around. Today the area includes the Regierungsviertel, Potsdamer Platz and the Kulturforum as well as the Diplomatenviertel.

Berliners make good use of the park for outdoor activities, sports and football games and grilling on Sundays is very popular. A large playground or Spielplatz is located on the southeastern corner near Potsdamer Platz. Some winters it is even possible to skate on the small lakes inside the park if weather conditions allow.
History of the Tiergarten
The former private hunting grounds of Great Elector Friedrich Wilhelm, the Grosse Tiergarten (large Game Park) had been used for the royal sport since the 16th century when it was first enclosed. The first avenues were arranged in the late 17th century, gaining increasingly refined touches under the influence of the French-inspired gardens for entertainment and leisure. The Strasse des 17. Juni its main west east axis leading to the Brandenburg Gate, originally known as Charlottenburger Chaussee (1698), it led to Charlottenburg Palace. In 1740 Friedrich the Great opened the first public gardens. The English influence became fashionable in the early 19th century and the original designs by prominent landscape architect, Peter Joseph Joseph Lenné, have lasted until today. In 1818 Lenné was commissioned to transform the green area into a landscaped park and the Zoological Garden on the southwestern edge of the Tiergarten was opened in 1844. A former road on the park\'s north-eastern side named In den Zelten (in the tents) was a place where, in the mid 18th century, refreshments were sold in elegant marquees. The beautiful buildings which flanked the park were destroyed by bombs during World War II. During the Nazi years, Albert Speer\'s grand master plan for Germania included the widening of the park’s central avenue – renaming it East-West Axis - and the Grosser Stern. During the war the park was used for the immediate necessities of firewood and as a vegetable garden.
Restoration of the Tiergarten after WW II
Like most of Berlin’s damaged monuments, restoration got under way in 1949 focussing on restoring as much vegetation as possible, including wilder areas. The result is a park of great beauty with diverse landscapes to discover as one wanders its avenues, pathways, lawns, meadows, ponds, flower beds – the rhododendrons in bloom are legendary - and landscaped gardens. Benches are tucked away for quiet contemplation. Pedal power taxis – or Velotaxis – are a lovely, if slightly lazier, way to go.
Popular retreats in the Tiergarten
Other popular retreats within the park are the Café am Neuen See – the small lake (Neuer See) can freeze up in winter and provides a wonderful northern winter landscape and in the summer it is transformed into a popular outdoor Self-Service Restaurant and Biergarten. Other well liked areas a very peaceful spot called Rousseau Island, and the English Gardens and coffee shop.</string>

    <string name="activities_name_kadewe_explanation">Berlin\'s most famous trademark department store is KaDeWe (Kaufhaus des Westens) – or \"department store of the west\". It is Berlin\'s shopping paradise, a favourite, easy to spot landmark on Wittenberg square. With 60,000 sqm, the equivalent of nine football fields, 380,000 articles, 40,000 visitors a day, this is the legendary, largest department store on the continent.
KaDeWe has been a Berlin institution for over one hundred years
The KaDeWe has survived the turmoil of 20th century German history unscathed. Beginning its commercial life in 1907, the store was a constant Berlin presence, its highs and lows reflecting those of the city. From World War I to the Golden Twenties consumer metropolis – the Depression and Nazi years and World War II - the Cold War and the 1950s \"Wirtschaftswunder\" - and finally German reunification in 1989. Through all the turbulence, KaDeWe retained its aura - somewhere between consumer temple and Berlin institution – intact. The store\'s 100th anniversary was a grand occasion celebrated in its 500sqm foyer with a gigantic cake.
From luxury fashion to gourmet food
Whether browsing through the ceramic department, letting your mouth water at the sight of a serving of champagne and oysters, buying praline truffles in the chocolaterie departement on the sixth floor Food Halls, or lingering in the fashion boulevards, shopping here is more than just shop-till-you drop - it\'s stocking-up on product awareness and consumer kudos in style.
The first years of KaDeWe
The department store, owned by Jewish retail entrepreneur Adolf Jandorf, first opened on Wittenberg Platz in 1907 with a 24,000 sqm retail surface. Designed by architect Emil Schaudt, it served the increasingly affluent middle class neighbourhood of the new Tiergarten district. In 1927 it was bought by the Warenhaus Hermann Tiez AG from whose initials the German retail giant Hertie gets its name. Founders of Hertie, the Jewish family Tietz, in business since 1882, made retail history by pioneering the new business model, acquired by Hermann during his time in the US - large turnovers at small profit and selling at fixed prices. Tietz bought Adolf Jandorf\'s store – KaDeWe - in 1926. It was at that time the largest department store in Europe with a 128 million Reichsmark turnover and 18,000 employees. In 1931 two floors were added to the original five and more extensions came in the 1990s, particularly the top of the world rooftop and Wintergarten where the self-service restaurant is today.
Nazi takeover of KaDeWe
In 1929 the Great Depression, followed by the 1933 Nazi takeover meant that the company was boycotted together with other non-Aryan businesses when the Nuremberg race laws were implemented. Forced to sell their shares the Tietz family left Germany but the store survived. Georg Karg was the Nazi\'s choice to manage KaDeWe and an 11 million loan from the Reich Ministry for Trade and Commerce followed. A restitution settlement in 1949 recognised the claims of the Tietz family heirs and the Karg Foundation renamed the group Hertie in 1972.
War damages
An American plane crashed into the building in 1943, devastating the building. It was rebuilt after WW2, unlike its competitor, the Wertheim department store in the Leipziger Straße, which was razed to the ground by the GDR authorities.
Booming post-war years
KaDeWe reopened on July 3, 1950, celebrating with over 180,000 visitors on the day. In the years of Germany\'s \"economic miracle\", economic recovery was underway and the new-look KaDeWe included the gourmet Food Hall, with a new touch of luxury and flair. In the immediate reunification days in November 1989 it was literally flooded by the largest numbers of visitors in its history, eager for a taste of consumer culture Western style. Hertie was bought by the Karstadt group in 1994. Since 2012 the KaDeWe is the property of the Signa Holding group. The current retail space comprises 60,000 sqm and two floors of gastronomic bliss with a splendid view, extremely popular with Berliners and visitors alike.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_ampelmann_shop_explanation">The \"Ampelmännchen\" was created in 1961 in East Germany as a road traffic signal for pedestrians. After the German unification, a design company developed a range of lifestyle products with the famous traffic light figure as its logo - which turned out to be a huge success.
Bags, watches and cuddly Ampelmanns
The eight Ampelmann shops across Berlin offer a variety of functional and design articles - from clothes and bags to watches and notebooks to jewellery and cuddly Ampelmann toys. The flagship store at the boulevard Unter den Linden - located at the very spot where the first Ampelmännchen traffic light was introduced - also serves coffee and sweets and provides information about the history of the East German Ampelmännchen. On top of that, the store holds a collection of over 30 traffic lights from all over the world.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_classic_remise_explanation">The Classic Remise Berlin, a center for vintage cars, was opened in 2003 in a historic tram depot, originally built in imperial times, construction starting in 1899. Some architectural changes to the building were made in the 1920s. There were limited damages in the war, the places where firebombs damaged the building can still be seen on the ceiling. After the tram system was given up in then West-Berlin in the 1960s the depot did not serve any purpose and was in decay until the present owners bought it in 2002 and started to reconstruct it into a classic car center.

Now there are garages, services and dealers for classic cars, shops for spare parts, clothing, model cars, accessories and restaurants in this landmark building.

For memorable events this is one of the most attractive locations in Berlin.

The old industrial architecture in combination with historic and classic vehicles will guarantee a unique automotive experience in the first classic car center of this kind worldwide. </string>
    <string name="activities_name_markthalle_neun_explanation">The Markthalle Neun in Berlin-Kreuzberg is one of the few remaining historic market halls from the 19th century. A landmark renovation and redesign of the old railway market hall was completed in 2011. Today, it is home to a large number of small dealers who offer fair, ecologically and regionally produced products.

Fresh produce such as fruits and vegetables, delicatessen and regional specialties, fish, meat and sausage, cheese, bread and bakery products, as well as products such as tea and coffee, beer, wine and spirits, are mainly available. Cafés and food stalls, flowers, crafts and services complete the offer.

Every Friday and Saturday the weekly market with products from the region invites to weekend shopping. At the \"Street Food Thursday\", visitors can discover the latest snack trends every Thursday night.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_berlin_philharmonic_explanation">Hans Scharoun\'s Philharmonie was the first building to be part of the Kulturforum. This was preceded by a competition design for the grounds of today\'s Freie Volksbühne near the Bundesallee. However, when a transfer to the southern edge of the Tiergarten was considered, Scharoun outlined the plan of a cultural forum abandoning the old street plan.

Terrain around the Philharmonie
As early as 1938, some buildings of the \"Geheimratsviertel\" had been demolished to make way for the \"round place\" of Speer\'s \"Germania\". During the war, the entire district was destroyed - left only the St. Matthew\'s.

Architect Hans Scharoun and the Philharmonic
The Philharmonie is regarded as Hans Scharoun\'s main work and as a model example of \"organic building\" - every building should evolve outwardly without any formal corset from its internal use. This approach, which was specially tailored to the respective construction contract, has earned Scharoun and the Philharmonic a great deal of criticism from architectural critics. Because unlike, for example, Mies van der Rohe\'s buildings, the Philharmonie could not become a school-educator, as a \"non-typeable unique\" it showed no way for the further reconstruction of West Germany.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_tierpark_explanation">The Berliner has a particularly close relationship to animals. No wonder that the traditional zoological garden lies in the middle of the city-west. More than 18,600 animals frolic on a 33-acre area right next to the same station and the Memorial Church. With around 1,400 species (including the aquarium), the zoo is one of the most biodiverse and interesting zoos in the world. Unforgotten is the polar bear Knut (2006-11), who became world famous after his birth in the enclosure.

History of the Zoological Garden
The animal kingdom was founded in 1844 on the initiative of the naturalists Alexander von Humboldt and Martin Lichtenstein, making it the first zoo in Germany. With the help of the garden artist Peter Joseph Lenné and well-known master builder an attractive area with antelope house (1872) and Persian tower (1910) was created for equine animals. The entrances, the Löwentor on Hardenbergplatz and the Elefantentor on Budapester Straße, are small works of art from around 1900.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_mall_of_berlin_explanation">The shopping area at the Mall of Berlin covers 76,000 square metres and is home to about 270 fashion, shoe and consumer electronic retailers, but also gift shops, a large food court and a supermarket. The building complex also includes places of entertainment, restaurants, a hotel, offices and apartments.
From fashion to food at the Mall of Berlin
In the basement of the mall, visitors can shop for gifts, cosmetics and convenience goods. While the ground floor accommodates upmarket fashion labels and fashion accessories, the shops on the first floor offer a selection of less pricey everyday fashion, footwear and jewellery. Stores on the second floor sell children\'s clothes. The food court is located on the second floor as well.
Shopping mall with a Piazza
Architectural highlight of the building is the piazza at the centre of the shopping mall. Situated under a vast curved glass roof, it offers views of the House of Lords of Prussia (seat of the German Federal Council) and protects shoppers from the elements. With more than 1,000 spaces, the underground car park provides ample parking opportunities.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_sony_center_explanation">Similar to the post-war period Hans Scharoun and Ludwig Mies van der Rohe today Frank O. Gehry and Helmut Jahn stand for two completely different architectural views. However, there is no direct confrontation, such as at the Kulturforum - Mies\'s \"house in itself\" versus Hans Scharoun\'s \"organic\" one-offs.

Architect Helmut Jahn and the Sony Center
Helmut Jahn, a native of Nuremberg and resident in Chicago since the 1960s, is seen as the exponent of the very commercial architecture against which Frank Gehry\'s \"deconstructivism\" opposes: glass high-rise giants, profitability-optimized office boxes, oversized shopping malls. But Jahn would not be in such demand if he was just a good engineer. His buildings stand out beneficially from the mass of \"utility architecture\", as long as one likes his style in principle. Examples are Berlin\'s narrowest office building on the corner of Kurfürstendamm / Lewishamstraße and the elegant Frankfurt Messeturm, at that time Europe\'s tallest building.

Architecture of the Sony Center
Jahn\'s most important project in Berlin is the Sony Center at Potsdamer Platz, a steel and glass-dominated ensemble of seven individual buildings. Here you will find offices, apartments, cinemas and restaurants, a \"movie house\" and the Sony European headquarters. The center of the triangular area is formed by the oval \"Forum\", which sees itself as part of the public urban space and therefore not separated from the surrounding streets. A spectacular engineering feat is the roof construction: The fanned-out canvas tent roof is fastened with tie rods to the steel ring resting on the surrounding buildings.

Striking components of the Sony Center
The most striking component is the glass high-rise, with 103 meters the tallest house in the square. It rounds off the Sony Center to Potsdamer Platz, with the semicircular south façade sliding upwards in front of the eastern narrow side. Noteworthy is also the view to the Bellevuestraße. Suspended from a steel bridge, the modern residential area spans the restored Neo-Baroque façade of the former noble hotel Esplanade.

Fragments of the Hotel Esplanade in the Sony Center
Since this only partially preserved prewar building on further floor could not be completely integrated into the new planning, two listed halls were \"relocated\". The 1300-ton \"Emperor\'s Hall\" was lifted in 1996 in a spectacular action on air cushions and moved by 75 meters. From the breakfast room, two walls remained in their original place, while the ceiling, floor and the other two walls were cut apart and reassembled on the other side of the esplanade.
Surroundings of the Sony Center
A third \"district\" was built in 2001-03 between Potsdamer Platz and Tiergarten. A part of the area is named after the builder Otto Beisheim, the founder of the retail chain Metro, \"Beisheim Center\". Dominant in the square are the two skyscrapers of Hans Kollhoff (Delbrück-Bank) and Hilmer, Sattler and Albrecht (Hotel Ritz-Carlton).</string>
    <string name="activities_name_aquadom_and_sealife_explanation">It consists of an acrylic glass container 16 meters high and 11.5 meters in diameter. Overall, the construction is 25 meters high. In the middle of the cylinder visitors can drive through the interior of the aquarium in an elevator. Around 1,500 fish from about 97 different species live in the aquarium in one million liters of water. At the same time the AquaDom is the exit of the Sea Life Berlin. Here, visitors can experience an extraordinary ride through the habitat coral reef.

The AquaDom was opened after several years of construction on December 2, 2003. The general contractor was a cooperation of the companies ICM and Müller-Altvatter. E. Sander supplied the systems engineering, Reynolds polymer the acrylic glass and the company Hydro Sight parts of the project supervision and the maintenance following the construction phase. The elevator was built by the GBH design Vierkirchen. The cost amounted to 12.8 million euros.

Union Investment Real Estate GmbH realized this project and the biological management lies with the Berlin Society for Large Aquariums (BGG). The aim of the BGG is to transform the AquaDom into an artificial coral reef to create a common habitat for fish and corals in the cylindrical aquarium.</string>
    <string name="activities_name_trabi_tour_explanation">Trabi Tour</string>

    <!-- PLACE ADRESSES -->

    <string name="museum_name_stasi_museum_address">Haus 1, Ruschestraße 103, 10365 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_ddr_museum_address">Karl-Liebknecht-Str. 1, 10178 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_museum_island_address">Museumsinsel Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_sans_souci_palace_address">Maulbeerallee, 14469 Potsdam</string>
    <string name="museum_name_holocaust_memorandum_address">Cora-Berliner-Straße 1, 10117 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_topography_of_terrors_address">Niederkirchnerstraße 8, 10963 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_berlin_wall_address">Bernauer Strasse 111, 13355 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_reichstag_address">Platz der Republik 1, 11011 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_marx_engels_forum_address">Karl-Liebknecht-Str., 10178 Berlin</string>
    <string name="museum_name_checkpoint_charlie_address">Friedrichstraße 43-45, 10117 Berlin</string>

    <string name="restaurants_name_curry_36_address">Mehringdamm 36, 10961 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_mustafas_gemuse_kebap_address">32 Mehringdamm, 10961 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_burger_meister_address">U1 Schlesisches Tor, Oberbaumstraße 8, 10997 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_vapiano_address">Rathausstraße 6, 10178 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_zola_address">Paul-Lincke-Ufer 39-40, 10999 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hasir_address">Nürnberger Str. 46, 10789 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_lindner_address">Rosenthaler Str. 33, 10178 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_block_house_address">Friedrichstraße 100, 10117 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hokey_pokey_address">Stargarder Str. 72, 10437 Berlin</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_oysterbar_kadewe_address">Tauentzienstraße 21-24, 10789 Berlin</string>

    <string name="sights_name_alexanderplatz_address">10178 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_potsdamer_platz_address">Potsdamer Platz Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_victoriapark_address">10965 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_brandenburg_gate_address">Pariser Platz, 10117 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_east_side_gallery_address">Mühlenstraße 3-100, 10243 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_hauptbahnhof_address">Hauptbahnhof, Europaplatz 1, 10557 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_gendarmenmarkt_address">Gendarmenmarkt, 10117 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_botanischer_garten_address">Königin-Luise-Straße 6-8, 14195 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_olympiastadion_address">Olympischer Platz 3, 14053 Berlin</string>
    <string name="sights_name_tiergarten_address">Tiergarten, Berlin</string>

    <string name="activities_name_kadewe_address">Tauentzienstraße 21-24, 10789 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_ampelmann_shop_address">Kurfürstendamm 20, Berlin, 10719 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_classic_remise_address">Wiebestraße 36 – 37, 10553 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_markthalle_neun_address">Markthalle Neun</string>
    <string name="activities_name_berlin_philharmonic_address">Berlin Philharmonic</string>
    <string name="activities_name_tierpark_address">Am Tierpark 125, 10319 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_mall_of_berlin_address">Leipziger Pl. 12, 10117 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_sony_center_address">Sony Center, Potsdamer Straße 4, 10785 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_aquadom_and_sealife_address">Spandauer Str. 3, 10178 Berlin</string>
    <string name="activities_name_trabi_tour_address">Zimmerstraße 97, 10117 Berlin</string>

    <!-- PLACE TELEPHONE NUMBERS -->

    <string name="museum_name_stasi_museum_telephone">030 5536854</string>
    <string name="museum_name_ddr_museum_telephone">030 84712373</string>
    <string name="museum_name_topography_of_terrors_telephone">030 2545090</string>
    <string name="museum_name_reichstag_telephone">030 22732152</string>
    <string name="museum_name_museum_island_telephone">030 266424242</string>

    <string name="restaurants_name_curry_36_telephone">030 2517368</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_mustafas_gemuse_kebap_telephone">030 2832153</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_burger_meister_telephone">030 23883840</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_vapiano_telephone">030 27890400</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_zola_telephone">01514 3596561</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hasir_telephone">030 2177774</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_lindner_telephone">030 24781507</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_block_house_telephone">030 20074377</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hokey_pokey_telephone">0176 80103080</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_oysterbar_kadewe_telephone">030 21210</string>

    <string name="sights_name_olympiastadion_telephone">030 30688100</string>
    <string name="sights_name_hauptbahnhof_telephone">030 2971055</string>
    <string name="sights_name_botanischer_garten_telephone">030 83850100</string>

    <string name="activities_name_tierpark_telephone">030 254010</string>
    <string name="activities_name_mall_of_berlin_telephone">030 20621770</string>
    <string name="activities_name_kadewe_telephone">030 21210</string>
    <string name="activities_name_ampelmann_shop_telephone">030 88728094</string>
    <string name="activities_name_classic_remise_telephone">030 3640780</string>
    <string name="activities_name_berlin_philharmonic_telephone">030 254880</string>
    <string name="activities_name_sony_center_telephone">030 419555000</string>
    <string name="activities_name_aquadom_and_sealife_telephone">030 992800</string>
    <string name="activities_name_trabi_tour_telephone">030 30201030</string>

    <string name="no_phone_number"></string>

    <!-- PLACE WEBSITES -->

    <string name="museum_name_stasi_museum_website">https://www.stasimuseum.de/en/enindex.htm</string>
    <string name="museum_name_ddr_museum_website">https://www.ddr-museum.de/en</string>
    <string name="museum_name_museum_island_website">https://www.smb.museum/en/museums-institutions/museumsinsel-berlin/home.html</string>

    <string name="museum_name_sans_souci_palace_website">https://www.spsg.de/en/palaces-gardens/object/sanssouci-palace/</string>
    <string name="museum_name_holocaust_memorandum_website">https://www.stiftung-denkmal.de/en/home.html</string>
    <string name="museum_name_topography_of_terrors_website">http://www.topographie.de/en/</string>
    <string name="museum_name_reichstag_website">https://www.bundestag.de/en/</string>


    <string name="restaurants_name_curry_36_website">https://www.curry36.de/</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_mustafas_gemuse_kebap_website">http://www.mustafas.de/</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_burger_meister_website">http://burger-meister.de/en/</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_vapiano_website">https://de.vapiano.com/en/home/</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_zola_website">https://www.facebook.com/zolakreuzberg/</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_hasir_website">http://hasir.de/index.php?id=24</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_lindner_website">https://www.lindner-esskultur.de/</string>

    <string name="restaurants_name_hokey_pokey_website">http://www.hokey-pokey.de/</string>
    <string name="restaurants_name_oysterbar_kadewe_website">https://www.kadewe.de/en/</string>

    <string name="sights_name_east_side_gallery_website">http://www.eastsidegallery-berlin.com/data/eng/index-eng.htm</string>
    <string name="sights_name_hauptbahnhof_website">https://www.bahnhof.de/bahnhof-de/Berlin_Hauptbahnhof-1029794</string>
    <string name="sights_name_botanischer_garten_website">https://www.bgbm.org/en</string>
    <string name="sights_name_olympiastadion_website">https://olympiastadion.berlin/en/home/</string>

    <string name="activities_name_kadewe_website">https://www.kadewe.de/en/</string>
    <string name="activities_name_ampelmann_shop_website">https://www.ampelmann.de/en/</string>
    <string name="activities_name_classic_remise_website">http://www.remise.de/</string>
    <string name="activities_name_markthalle_neun_website">https://markthalleneun.de/</string>
    <string name="activities_name_berlin_philharmonic_website">https://www.berliner-philharmoniker.de/en/</string>
    <string name="activities_name_tierpark_website">https://www.tierpark-berlin.de/en</string>
    <string name="activities_name_mall_of_berlin_website">https://www.mallofberlin.de/en</string>
    <string name="activities_name_aquadom_and_sealife_website">https://www.visitsealife.com/de/en/berlin/</string>
    <string name="activities_name_trabi_tour_website">http://www.trabi-world.com/</string>

    <string name="no_web_site"></string>

    <string name="web_site">Web Site</string>
</resources>
